Ryan Thomas

234 Norton Street Leichhardt N.S.W. 2040 Australia Mobile: +61 448 366 061

Email: ryan@ryant.org

Profile

I draw my expertise from a diverse range of experience in both software and non-software related roles. My technical background is primarily the development and operation of large-scale distributed systems, and setting the strategic direction for development groups.

- Strong knowledge of distributed systems and their fundamentals.
- Demonstrated ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously.
- Technically minded with the ability to quickly adapt to an ever changing environment.
- Strong leader with a track record for growing impactful teams.

Skills and Technical Experience

Languages: Java, Rust, Go, SQL

Cloud Providers: GCP, AWS

Operating Systems: Linux, OS X, Windows

Vehicle Licences: MR (Medium Rigid), R (Motorcycle), PPL(A) (Private Pilot, Fixed Wing)

Professional Experience

Google, Australia Engineering Manager — Accelerated Storage SRE November 2017 — Current

The Accelerated Storage SRE team is responsible for building and managing a number of high-throughput, low-latency systems critical to the success of the business. My role is to grow out the team in Sydney, and along with our sister team in Seattle set and drive strategic programs of work, as well as technical growth in the team members.

Google, Ireland Technical Program Manager — Search SRE October 2014 — November 2017

As a part of the Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) group my focus was driving strategic projects for the Search Serving team as well as collaborative projects in the serve, crawl and indexing teams.

This role requires me to develop programs of work, achieve buy-in from globally distributed teams, define deliverables and expectations as well as track work through the project and program lifecycles.

Due to the geographical distribution of the teams (Mountain View, New York, Zurich, Dublin, Sydney) definition of work and delegation to other program managers is essential.

Previous Employment

Atlassian, Sydney, N.S.W. Engineering Team Lead December 2009 — October 2014

Leading multiple teams, I have taken on many challenging projects and have been able to deliver on time and without cutting scope.

The projects have generally been in the area of how Atlassian delivers software to its hosted platform, and most recently an ongoing project to develop and deliver an internal PaaS for hosting and deploying services inside of Atlassian.

This role has required me to manage engineering resources, liaise with project stakeholders, set (& reset) project goals and present justification of the projects to executives.

The projects I have run:

- Develop an internal PaaS for Atlassian (think private Heroku), this is a cross-organisational project **Ongoing**
- Design & build a mechanism to track hosted software delivery from development through to production.
- Design & build a framework to orchestrate the upgrade of 90,000 JVMs in the Atlassian OnDemand environment.
- Managed the integration of customers and Atlassian Partners into the Confluence 4.0 ecosystem.
- Build the Confluence Continuous Deployment infrastructure used internally at Atlassian, this was then picked up by other product teams.

I am an accomplished public speaker and have presented on a waide variety of topics across a number of internal and external conferences.

Objective Corporation Limited, North Sydney, N.S.W. Software Engineer / Enterprise Search Specialist August 2009 — December 2009

My role at Objective Corporation was to take ownership of the search and indexing services of the Objective Software Suite and provide guidance and support for the current and future implementations. These services utilise Verity's K2 search server and I was tasked with investigating and prototyping a replacement; with Apache Solr being the selected at the time.

Australian Defence Force — Army Trainee Pilot March 2008 — June 2009

I have completed the Australian Defence Force Basic Pilots Course and Army Intermediate Pilots Course and hold a military endorsement for the PAC CT-4B aircraft for day and night operations.

The training I have received during my time as an officer in the Army has given me experience in the management of personnel on the ground, in a multi-crew airborne environment and in the making of time critical decisions.

Oracle Corporation, North Ryde, N.S.W. Senior Software Engineer
March 2007 — March 2008

Hyperion Solutions, North Sydney, N.S.W. Software Engineer
December 2005 — March 2007

TransActive Systems, Gosford, N.S.W. Software Developer / Technical Support July 2004 — December 2005

BAE Systems, Williamtown, N.S.W. Software Developer (intern)
July — September 2003

Qualifications

Master of Science (Computer Science) Georgia Institute of Technology. 2017 — Current Georgia, United States of America

Certificate of Advanced Project Managment Stanford. 2015 — 2016 California, United States of America

Bachelor of Engineering — Software Engineering The University of Newcastle. 2001 — 2005 New South Wales, Australia

Certificate III — Resource Operations Australian Army, September 2005

Certificate III — Business (Frontline Management) Australian Army, September 2005

Certificate III — Government Australian Army, September 2005

Certificate III — Transport & Distribution (Road Transport) Australian Army, April 2002

Higher School Certificate Corpus Christi College, Tuggerah. 1999 — 2000

Professional Credentials

$\begin{array}{l} \textbf{Professional Member} \\ \textbf{Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)} \\ 2005 -- 2012 \end{array}$

Bombardier

Royal Australian Artillery, Australian Army Reserve2000 - 2010

Referees

Available on request.